# Jeremy Li

<u>www.jeremyli.space</u> Tel: (781)-605-7163 jeremyli.0623@gmail.com

39 Florence St, Boston, MA

# Objective

A software engineer also can get hooked on product. Couple years software engineering experiences not only bolster my technical capability but nurture product visions and business acumen. I have a very strong focus on product usability in the work and love to take actions on digging feature insights. I desire to launch captivated products that can help our customer be successful. Will learn whatever is needed to bring values on my team.

## **Work Experiences**

## Microsoft Crop, Bellevue Square, WA

## **Software Engineer,** Microsoft Teams

Jun, 2020 - Now

• Primarily working on MWT (Modern Work Transformation) targeting product line to increase MS Teams application's rich interactions with users, helps targeting gain higher MAU goal by achieving 600K from 450K.

### Veracode, Inc, Burlington, MA

#### Software Engineer, Developer Integration

Mar, 2018 – May, 2019

#### As being engineer,

- Built friction-less third-party plugins/toolings to support user-friendly security customer community.
- Scaled Jira standalone server over AWS cloud-based ecosystem to reduce massive single point failures and refined technical requirements with team and achieved existing user's conversion rate from nothing to 21%.
- Worked on mitigating security risks by triaging security attacks and internal data compliance vulnerabilities.

#### As being PM side role,

- Built up customer metrics via SumoLogic pipeline to track real-time API calling through the entire integration eco-system (7 product lines), facilitate Sr. management and partnership to make strategic decisions.
- Involved proactively in Agile Scrum and DevOps process (A/B testing, canary releases) to enable fully CI/CD pipeline, gained better product sense and SaaS enterprise insights.
- Gathered customer feedback (Webex/Email/On-site) and refined user persona for integration features.
- Collaborate with designers and engineers to be a liaison for cross-functional process and development.

## **CA Technologies, Burlington, MA** (Acuqired Veracode in Nov, 2017)

## Software Engineer, Developer Integration

Nov, 2017 – Mar, 2018

• Implement and maintain a range of plugins/extensions of SaaS application security scan platform, led to increase at least 20% efficiency of proceeding application security scanning assessment.

## Associate Software Engineer, Core Platform

Jun, 2016 - Nov, 2017

- Tackled customer-faced technical problems and refactored the deprecated codebase.
- Launched visual studio extension into Microsoft Marketplace and got 6000+ downloads in 3 months.
- Been UX council member dedicated to my team, to unify and adopt best practice of front-end engineering.

## Philips of North America, New York

### Software Research Intern, Acute Care Solution

Sep - Dec, 2014

Processed, transformed large-scale healthcare dataset that can be later used for EMR research purposes.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: Java, JavaScript/ES6, C#, Python, HTML5/CSS(Sass/LESS)
Web Framework: React, D3.js, .NET Core, Bootstrap, Gradle, Gulp, REST
Certification: PSM I (Professional Scrum Master). Google Analytics IO

#### Education

### Northeastern University, College of Engineering, Boston, MA

M.S. in Information Systems

Sep, 2015

Related Course: Application Engineering, Web Development, Advanced Data Science, Organization Mgt.

#### Central South University, College of Engineering, China

B.S. in Computational Material Engineering

Jun, 2013

Awards: 2nd prize in Challenge Cup Innovative Technology; "Most Influential Member", Engineer-Club. Leadership: College Vice-President of Innovation and Entrepreneurship Association.

## **Academic Projects**

## U.S. Airlines On-Time Performance Analytics Project

Cleaned, transformed large-scale datasets from RITA, visualized on-time performance as graphs and charts.